Men only want three things,
and to be quite honest, it's disgusting.
Every man dreams of having a warehouse
they could reverse their sports car into.
And in that warehouse,
they probably just have a bed,
some weights, and some peace
and quiet. The other thing
that men dream about
is stealth camping on a roundabout.
You're driving round a roundabout,
see some decent foliage, and you think to
yourself, "I could sleep in there.
No one would even know that I
was in there." Just like Steve.
Then every man dreams of having thick
follicle density and a good hairline.
But let's not get into that.
I shaved it out of choice.
I wanted to have a shaved head.
In this video,
I'm going to explain to you why it's
imperative that any business,
personal brand,
or creator should look to get
their own space.
Because for my businesses to thrive,
I have to be creative.
I have to think about the title,
the thumbnail,
what I'm going to talk about, and
how it's going to serve you, so
that some of you end up doing business
with me.
If I can't be creative,
I can't operate the business to its full
potential.
So for instance,
even though this could seem like a random
video, here's the
outlier.
One of my videos recently performed so
well, I'm now modeling the title
with a slightly different angle.
The avatar for this video
is one of my good
friends called Durin Cartel.
He's got over a million followers,
and he's filming
from a spare room in his house,
and I think that's holding him
and his brand and
his potential back.
So I'm going to speak to Durin in this
video because I know
there are thousands of Durins watching
this.
And then there'll be an offer in the
video, which is to work with me.
There'll be a link in the description.
But let's not even get distracted from
that yet. It wasn't always this way.
For the first 27 years of my life,
I had to work to deliver.
Whether it was in a shitty corporate job,
I had to deliver results, KPIs, key
performance indicators. And when I
was a personal trainer,
I had to deliver the
personal training sessions on the floor.
Whether I was creative or not,
it didn't make a difference.
But when I took my businesses online,
everything had to change.
I had to go from someone
that delivers work to becoming a creative.
I entered a game,
and I've been playing the game for 10
years, where the better my
ideas, the more money
is in my bank account at the end of the
month.
Sounds crazy, but that
is literally how this game is played.
When I have a video that booms,
that goes really well,
that gets loads of views, it
sends loads of people into my lead magnet,
clients pop out the end, money's in the
bank account.
My impressions on social media
and my income move
together.
So whenever I'm a little bit skint,
the pressure to make good ideas
comes,
and when I'm making really good money,
sometimes I get a bit slack and not
post on social media.
I got diagnosed with ADHD when I
was an adult.
I didn't even find out until I was 34.
But I don't really talk about it
that much because it feels
that most people are
just talking about it to get engagement
or clickbait, or just they're boring in
their content, so they try
and have an identity.
"Oh, look at me,
I've got ADHD." There have always been
signs that I've got a
really bad attention deficit.
My friends would've told you way before I
even found
out. But the worst part is,
as Declan knows here, I'm very impulsive,
to the point that
when I have an idea for a piece of
content, "Declan, where are
you? Get to the gym.
We need to film today.
I need it out by 3:00 PM."
But also impulsive like,
"I'm going to wrap my car
another color.
I'm going to pre-order a GT3 RS.
I want to change my exhaust.
I want to change my exhaust again.
I want to build a room so I can have air
con.
I need to have a safety squat bar."
And when the impulsivity hits,
I have to get it.
It's like scratching an itch.
I can't do anything until I do the thing
that I'm thinking about.
The reason that my fiancée is with me,
because she's the only woman in my life
that's understood me, and she goes,
"You've got an idea, just piss off.
Go film it." Because she knows I'm not
going to be there for the rest of the day
unless I get the idea out of my head,
which is why she sends me here to the
warehouse, to the bat cave. Now,
not a lot of people know this,
but I used to be a
low-key drug addict. Upstairs,
I have got... Do you know what, Declan?
Let's not show them. Let's tell them. Oh,
Jesus Christ. Too many steps.
Do you know what that is? Modafinil.
That is a narcolepsy drug that people
are supposed to take to stop them falling
asleep during the day.
I would low-key smash anything
that could help me lock in.
Modafinil is how I wrote three books in
three years. Gives you dry mouth.
If you ever need anything,
I'm your dealer.
Being a young man,
don't you go meet dealers.
I'll get the drugs for you.
So when it came to making Nootonic, I
was someone that had a really bad
attention
deficit disorder. Everyone
that works with me low-key knows I'm
semi-retarded, but
when I can be productive,
I can produce good work and good ideas.
Now, before this, it's worth noting,
I did get to a million followers
and do very
well, but before this,
I had to use a café.
I couldn't work at home.
And for a lot of you watching this,
you'll be the same as me.
My home is my place I relax and nap.
Where I used to masturbate.
I don't want to be working
and trying to close clients in the same
room that I
masturbate in. Be in the kitchen.
A lot of people don't realize
that Starbucks
never marketed themselves as a coffee
shop.
They were supposed to be the third space.
You're supposed to have your work,
you're supposed to have your home,
and then
you're supposed to have a third space.
So if you wanted to read a book,
don't read your book at home because your
kids are
going to be there,
and your husband's going to be asking you
about stuff.
Instead,
read your book in the third place because
you're not going to read it at
work. So for me, for years, same café,
same seat,
same order, good one, Bondi,
did the same single thing every single
day.
And when I got in there, headphones on,
world off.
I couldn't work at home,
never worked at home,
didn't write one single word of my
book at home.
Had to go somewhere to get work done.
Now, a lot of you
are probably going to resonate with this.
Now,
what allowed me to 10X my business
and my brand was
appreciating that my brain
was never going to change.
That low-key level of obsessiveness,
being distracted, maybe some low-key
autism, whatever it is, that
was never going to change.
I can use supplements,
now I can use Nootonic,
and I can use caffeine to lock in,
but ultimately,
I can't expect my environment to change
for me.
I have to change the environment.
So I built this space.
And the funny thing is, Declan today said,
"I wish I had a warehouse.
Can't wait to have one." You said your
friend that did the roller shots for the
GT3, these clips
that you're watching right now,
he wants to get the
one next door.
And you're probably wondering how much I
pay a month for this space,
and I'll tell you in just a second.
But another thing to make clear
is you don't
need all of this space. Even
if you guys were to get a room,
even just this big,
Durin, you can create a backdrop,
and there's even YouTube channels at the
moment
that use a TV behind them to create a
depth of field.
So instead of having a studio they change,
they've just got a big screen TV that
they film in front of.
Everything you've been watching so far has
been a lie.
It's just
A TV screen
So even in the infancy of your journey,
rather than just having a plain wall
behind
you, you could use a TV
and it would look really cool.
What did you just ask?
So if you do get the GT3 RS,
how much money are you going to lose?
Since I've had that for two years
and I've done quite a few miles in it,
probably
lose 100 grand. £50,000. I'd be happy
if I got 350.
But everyone out there thinks you've got
to get appreciating asset.
You've got to
buy a house. House is going to go up.
You've got inflation.
Declan, I'm a depreciating asset.
When you met me, I had hair. Look at me.
How many times have I been injured since
we met from doing nothing?
I threw my back out doing nothing, Declan.
I've got 10 years left of prime.
I'm as close to 50 as I am to 23.
So the thing
is,
sorry to go on a tangent of this video,
the GT3 RS and the GT3 are probably two of
the best cars that will ever be created.
And the car creation curve has hit a point
where it's only going to decline from
here on in. The new Nissan Skyline,
it's electric.
The BMW M3, going electric. This
is the peak time to have a car.
If you're going to waste your money on
anything,
why not have it be the thing that
just fucking every time you see it--
I park my car, get out,
and then I just look
at it. I just admire it, Declan.
I love that car.
And instead of buying an investment
property, which is an appreciating asset,
I
might just buy the RS,
a depreciating asset. That
is all of humanity.
Think of all the famine, the wars,
the bubonic plague, the fall
of Rome. Imagine
when people in the Victorian times
were chucking shit out into the
street.
Our ancestors went through all of
that so I could be here.
It's not about being able to afford it.
Can I have a piece of history? Yes.
I should take that with two hands.
Here's a question.
Have you bought everything you've wanted
to buy so far?
Is there anything else
that you want to do financially?
Financially? Oh, yeah.
I've never really liked Ferraris,
but I'd like to have one.
Outside of cars, have you set family up?
Have you got the house you want to have?
No, because we're not there yet, Declan.
But the thing is,
I think about this as well.
The more I set up my son,
the more of a prick he's going to be.
Everything from here on in
is all bullshit anyway.
I've got my Maslow hierarchy of needs.
They've been set a long time.
You've got your Maslow hierarchy of needs,
my head.
Everything else is just bullshit from here
on in.
But now,
tell me one mate of yours who inherited
money who's sound?
Exactly. You got any rich mates? Mummy
and Daddy money?
So really the best thing I can do for my
son is spend it all. Back to the video.
[chuckles] But the tangents are fun.
Hold on, I've lost my trail of thought.
Okay, Declan,
I've been going out for night drives.
The other night, oh my God,
let me show you this.
A friend of mine sent me this.
He's got the exact same car as me.
[upbeat music]
A friend of mine was having some Nutonic
Focus pouches.
Just took his car out for a drive
listening to "Dancing in the Moonlight" by
Toploader. You know that song, right?
Yeah.
Thank God. So for me,
I had a creative bottleneck.
So, "Oh,
I want to film a podcast with my friends.
Oh,
it's free on Thursday at 2:00 PM." Cool.
Now I've just got to think about this
conversation that I can't fucking have
till
2:00 PM on Thursday. Oh, my friend Lockie,
who owns The Locker Room in Sydney, we
used to film in his gym. I was like, "Oh,
Lockie, can I use your gym, please?" Had
to do it on a Sunday morning. So again,
any gym-based content, I had to wait till
fucking Sunday. The crazy thing is, I
was there flying business class around the
world,
but having to beg my friend to open his
gym on a Sunday morning so I could
film a few videos. Pathetic.
And the third was I loved living with my
mates, but I would film at home so that
if my mate was on a work call, I was
just sat in my room with my dick in my
hands waiting for him to get off a work
call
so I could film a piece of content to call
someone a cunt online.
That is not good for my brain.
I'm sat there thinking, "Hurry up.
Finish your fucking work call." Or
if it's Monday and I want to teach someone
about
hip hinge, I've got to wait till Sunday.
This, for me,
is not a good use of my mental way of
doing
things. So by building a space,
I got to alleviate that.
I got to empty the bottlenecks in my
process, creating flow.
I also don't like batch recording content.
Some people sit in a room for six hours,
and they'll film 100 videos. Not for me.
I like to get the idea, run with it,
do my best.
I like to post it straight away.
People go, "Oh,
if you post it tomorrow at 7:00
PM,
you might get more views." I don't care.
I'll do another video by tomorrow at 7:00
PM. I chase the dopamine.
And every video we put out,
I'll look at the performance,
and it's going one of
two ways. Either that video performs well,
and I'm like, "Oh my God,
dopamine. I'm the fucking boss."
Or the video bombs, and that's fine.
I use that to create an internal narrative
where I just beat myself up and I go,
"If you don't make a better video,
you're a piece of shit."
And then you're just
pretty much living between two of those.
Either it does well
and you're happy for a short period of
time, or it doesn't do
well, and you need to raise the game
and do better. What's that, Declan?
A nine out of 10? Do you want a job? No,
I'm joking. That was my video.
Yeah, I like to get the idea
and run with it.
It's just the way I like to do it.
Batch content might work for some of you,
not for me.
Like I said, because I'm mental.
We'll go downstairs.
So this entire space,
including a bathroom, a shower, the two
offices we built up there,
the podcast studio,
which we'll film in a second, and
that little room,
it's about £1,500 a month.
So this is cheaper than anything else
that I have.
Declan,
you cost me significantly more than this
room. Just think of it that way.
I could live in here.
I sometimes think about living in here.
I sometimes think if the economy really
goes to shit, I'll bring my family here,
and we'll be happy.
And there'll be part of me inside
that would low-key quite like
living in a warehouse.
I don't know what that is.
It's just part of the male psychology.
Dudes watching this will testify.
One of the main reasons you want to have a
space like this is I can express myself
and be as fucking weird as I want because
it's my space. It's my home.
You know sometimes
when you're at a friend's house,
and you're just a bit awkward,
a bit weird. But when people
are around your house,
you get to be whatever you want
to be.
That's what you can do in your own space.
Now, before Declan, all I had
was a tripod.
400,000 YouTube subscribers I got on my
own using this, where quite literally,
I'd walk around the gym,
talk to the camera,
change the angle for a scene change.
And it meant that I could be in here
having lols on my own and getting content
done. So in the onset,
filmed for years on my bedroom floor.
When I got the space,
still did years just carrying around a
tripod.
Even without a videographer,
you could do so much.
But don't worry, Declan,
you're not going to be out of a job.
AI may replace your editing,
but it won't replace you over there.
What's that, 50 mil? Or is
that a variable? So yeah, that variable.
That's where the money's at.
There's something we need to talk about,
which is what
I call the subconscious aspirational.
Even right now, you watching this,
behind me, YouTube plaque.
It's an appeal to authority.
James has got the audience on YouTube.
I could get the same.
I'm out of breath from running upstairs.
Three times online bestselling author.
Have them there.
Subconscious aspirational.
By me teaching you things
and having the authority behind me,
you're associating
the two. And for any of you that
are aspirational, you're like,
"I'm going to
listen to him because he's done it."
And then, yeah, just the Nutonic.
Going to raise that $100 million valuation
at the end of the year.
Don't worry about it.
But what I want to show you is on YouTube,
this backdrop
that we used here
was subconscious aspirational because of
the depth of field we
had behind.
This was before we'd built this,
and I said to Declan, "Let's flip it
around." By showcasing the warehouse,
it's got a bit of an authority, like this
guy's not just shooting in his garage.
He's got depth.
Before that, I was shooting at home,
and my manager said to me, he was like,
"Bro,
don't shoot in your spare room.
You're more credible than that.
You've accomplished more than shooting in
your spare room." And I was like, "Fair
play." So I spent 60 grand on building
this studio.
Now, Kai Stone, this guy here,
what we like about him,
he had a bit of an outlier
with 21,000 views in five days.
And even though his filming setup looks a
bit
archaic,
you can actually notice the swimming pool,
the grass, the river in the
background.
His background does more here for his
credibility than anything
else. The ping pong table,
all of these things that creators do are
intentional. Now,
I know some others off the top of my head.
William Brown. So straight away,
Dubai high-rise behind
him.
He wears his gold Rolex in almost all of
his
videos. Or maybe not this one.
Hope business is good, bro.
Who else does it? Oh
Charlie Morgan.
Some of his best-performing videos.
Look at this, 544,000. Fact he went,
took a picture
outside a villa on the Palm,
and then let's just watch the first part
of this
video.
All right. It's a cloudy day.
He's not showing us a cloudy day.
He's showing,
"I'm living on the fucking Palm in
Dubai," which is one of the most expensive
places to live on the world.
In Dubai. It's very rare.
It rained last night, believe it or-
He's not talking about the weather.
You know what I mean?
So straight away,
there's an appeal to authority.
Now he's going to walk through his fucking
massive house, to then get to his
whiteboard. So the first minute,
if he had started the video here,
you'd go, "Bro,
this looks fucking shit house."
But the beginning part of the video was to
establish authority. Again,
if we think about this
subconscious inspirational. So we have
this one did very well,
sat in front of a GT3, this one GT3,
this one GT3,
using the car as a bit of a bucket.
So even though we spoke there about the
GT3 RS,
it would cost me about 200,000 pounds to
upgrade, which I
know is a lot,
but then from a business
and creativity standpoint, could I make
more content with it?
Would it be good for the subconscious
inspirational concept?
Also,
would it then become something that'd be
really good at driving me new views,
which I could then monetize using my
offer?
So even having that car there
is a 9.5 times outlier.
I've nearly 10X'd my views by utilizing
the title we're doing here and the
car. So really, is
that a 200,000-pound investment into
not just more downforce,
15 more horsepower, and the PDK gearbox?
It's an investment into my future,
just like the studio.
So here again, I'm ashamed to say it,
I had to play the game on this.
One of the reasons that I shot in my car,
subconscious aspirational.
A lot of people,
when they watch your stuff
and you're watching mine, you don't
really give a shit about me.
You give a shit about you,
and that's fine, but I
am your canary in the mine.
I am the rat in the
maze that you're utilizing to whether
or not you believe something can happen.
And again, that's completely fine.
So when you see some balding, mid-rigged
personal trainer who just posted on the
social media for nine years, drive your
dream car, you're not thinking about me,
you're thinking about you, and you're
going, "If he can do it, I can do it,
because I'm better looking and I've got a
better hairline." Subconscious
aspirational.
You want your life to be something
that people can aspire to,
not because they
care, but because they want it to. Okay,
moving on.
One of the most important things you can
think about when spending money is
something called an ROI,
a return on investment.
In ads, we call this a ROAS,
return on ad spend.
So for instance,
the webinar I did over the weekend,
thanks to everyone that
attended, we spent $20,000 on the
signups for 12,000 people to sign up.
We managed to convert 1% to make 120K,
so our ROAS would
be six,
and we still have thousands of emails to
convert.
So that's a return on ad spend for any of
you that maybe haven't spoken about that.
But return on investment. So that car,
from a return on investment standpoint,
although it's cost me quite a lot of
money, it's opened up networking.
I've gone to track days.
I've actually met a couple billionaires,
weirdly, through having that car,
and they've put me in touch with the
people that
invested into Nutonic. So having that,
just from a networking perspective,
great. The day I bought that,
people within my network came to me for
business
advice because that signaled to everyone,
"He's doing all right." Not doing that
well. But anyway,
the return on investment sometimes can be
subjective with
relationships, with the track days
that I can go to, the fact that I've got
connects at Porsche. But also,
the return on investment can be truly
tangible.
So for instance,
1,500 per car on the month.
To be honest, when you add bills
and whatnot, it's probably nearer,
let's call
it 20 to 22K per year.
You can't even get a junior member of
staff
that's come out of university for that.
So for a start, you've got that.
The next thing to consider is this
is a legitimate business expense.
So the money I'm spending here
and the money I'm spending on Declan,
my business
pays for that, not me with money
that I've pulled out and paid tax on.
So this just reduces my profitability.
So although my business
is less profitable,
I manage to save time using Declan, and
I get a facility that I can use here.
Again, an incredible return on investment.
Now, the truth is, if my business makes,
let's just say, a
million pounds a year,
I've got to ask myself,
"Is this investment
into a space going to help me?
Is it going to help me produce more
content?" Almost
definitely. How much more?
Maybe two times as much.
Maybe three times as much.
How better is that quality of content
going to perform?
Is it going to increase my average view
duration?
Is it going to increase the click-through
rate?
Because using thumbnails in this space,
like the thumbnail for this video, that
space is one of the things
that entices you to watch.
So if I see an uplift of 3 to 4%, which
is fucking
nothing, it already washes its face,
it already pays for itself.
Now, again,
if I was just to come to you and I
was to grab that person, Darren, my
friend, Darren Cartel,
if you're watching this.
Darren,
we've been having this conversation for
two years, but you're still not
listening to me.
The guy decided to live in Clapham,
the most expensive place in
the developed world,
where you're just never going to get a
place like this, which
brings me onto my next point.
But before we get there, if I
was to take you,
Darren, and put you here, or you, Declan,
put you here, or you, Mate, and put you
here, would all of this allow you
or permit you to
increase your output by 3 to 4%? If no,
stay where the fuck you are. But if yes,
you should very much consider this.
Now, the elephant in the room
is the only reason that this costs such a,
can I say affordable? Yeah,
affordable rate, is that I am not where I
used to live. So about three years ago,
I had a decision to make, and I've been
living in Bondi for five years.
I love Bondi. I love the Eastern suburbs.
I love everything about it.
But one of the reasons I never had a space
like this
was it would be very difficult,
not only that,
it'd be very difficult financially
to afford this kind of space in a part of
Sydney like that.
And if I was to get a place that
was more affordable, maybe out west, maybe
Marrickville,
I would then be stuck in traffic,
worse quality of life.
I'd be spending places going wherever.
So I made a decision three years ago to
move away from where
I would love to live,
so Darren in Clapham.
Say if he was to move to Woking
or Guildford or anywhere in Surrey, for
instance,
he would remove himself from all the
things that he loves. That's fine.
But for me, the decision was, okay,
if I remove myself and get this facility,
I can still go visit my friends an hour
away.
I can still nip to Sydney whenever I need.
I get to do it in my favorite car.
But ultimately, you can't have both
If you wanna be a creative and a
creator,
and you want to live in the coolest
fucking place you can, it's going to
be at the sacrifice of having a place
that you can go to to be your best self,
your
creative self, and to pump out content.
And for me, I said, "You know what?
I'm going to take five years,
I'm going to move away from my friends,
I'm going to
lock the fuck in,
and then maybe in five years' time,
I'll have enough free
capital that I can go back,
buy a bigger house,
and get one of these near all of my
friends." And it just turns out I don't
miss Bondi at all.
I actually love it down here.
I love how quiet it is.
I live near Wollongong,
which people don't think is sexy,
but I'm like, "I have
this entire lad pad to myself to work."
And the best thing, I don't even pay for
this. My business does. Wow.
Any questions from that?
Would you move back to Bondi at some
point, you think?
No, it's too hectic now. I go back,
it stresses me out.
I was there on Saturday, I was like,
"Fuck, where do I park?" Which is, yeah.
But that could just be me getting old.
You should move to Bondi, actually, no.
Because you're in a similar situation now.
You're living back with your mum,
which I think is great,
but now you're saving
yourself money. You've got space.
You've got a spare room
that you're using for work.
Yeah.
You have no stress, no outgoings,
no bills, because you
are now spending three
years developing yourself to get to a
position where you're like, "I can now go
where I want." So here's an analogy.
So let's say you and I have hit our
maximum amount of reps in a lift, and
we can't get any higher.
We might want to just drop the weight
down-
Make sense, yeah
... work on the technique,
get the technique perfect,
and work your way back up and
break through that plateau.
So it's the exact same thing we would do
in training
principles that we're doing with our life.
And it's not really like, "Oh, no,
feel sorry for me." I love my life down
here.
So for a lot of people, sometimes,
why don't you just move to a cheaper area
for a
few years? Those of you in the UK,
go to Portugal,
get a warehouse in the middle
of nowhere. As long as you've got Wi-Fi,
sunny weather, good coffee, you can do
whatever the fuck you want. So in tax,
there is something called benefit in kind,
and sometimes the tax man, ATO, HMRC,
will try and
pin something on you and go, "Okay,
that could be exclusively
and wholly for the
business, but we believe that you
were using that for some personal
benefit." So
the crazy thing is, in this room, ATO,
if you're watching, do any personal
workouts get done in here?
Unfortunately not.
Every single workout I do
is to promote my coaching at the Jameson
Academy.
I wish I could come in here,
use it for personal use, but I can't.
This sauna, Declan, you might think
that that's used for personal.
Unfortunately, it's not. This
is used because I'm performing a study
that I'm going
to conduct and post online about the
impacts of infrared sauna on recovery.
Might even become a dissertation.
I wish I could use it for my own personal
use, Declan, but it's just for work.
There's no benefit in kind here.
Not your thinking, Declan.
This Nutonic fridge is for promotion.
I wish I could use this to drink my own
tonic, but unfortunately,
these aren't even
drinks for me.
They're drinks for my staff.
This is exclusively
and wholly for the business.
Now, one day in a perfect world,
I wish that I could use this as a place
for my own personal needs. But until
that day, this is all 100% used
for business. Ah.
That's why at the moment,
when you're living at home, you could
say that you're using the spare room for
business, but your accountant only gives
you a certain amount. They're like,
"Come on, mate,
there's a bit of benefit in
kind there, because
when your nan comes over,
she needs somewhere to stay, and
that's the place they'll get you."
But yeah, honestly,
one day I just wish I could
use this for personal stuff.
You're probably thinking, "Why
is there a baby cot and
crash here?" That's because my fiancée,
Tay, she also makes content.
She's trying to appeal to mums. So Kian,
my son, he's not in there for
personal use. He's a prop in the video.
And if Tay can't lift Kian
and use him in the video,
it's bad for algorithmic
views. So yeah, unfortunately,
everything you see here
is with the business in
mind. So this room here,
I'm not actually sure what to do with.
For you guys watching this,
please do help me in the comments whether
or not we
turn this into another content room.
I have always thought about maybe having
it as a staff room, but everyone that
works with me just ends up quitting. Mad.
Just not sure what to do here.
But again, like I say, unlimited budget.
If this was yours,
what would you do with it? This
is the main room that we use.
Everything you see content-wise,
down this end.
We black out the blinds so
that we can control the light in here.
We've got one FX3 here shooting down here.
We're thinking of putting another FX3 down
here.
This means I can come in here,
I can point, I can shoot.
The light is all controlled.
And it means if I have a good idea,
I can literally
run down here, put a card in the camera,
press record, beep. Happy days.
And the best part is, having two setups,
I can do this.
There's a comedian
that a lot of people know. It's left on,
the light's on.
Oh, well. Called Jerry Seinfeld,
and he makes it a point
that he has to sit in a
room for two hours to come up with
creative material.
Now,
it's completely fine for him to come sit
in the room and not have any creative
material,
but he won't let himself not go sit in the
room.
So sometimes what I do is,
if I haven't got any good ideas for
content, I come
here, I sit here.
I literally leave the house,
and I come and devote that
time, an hour,
and the only thing I'm doing in
that hour is coming up with content
ideas. Whether it's ideation for titles,
thumbnails, whatever it is.
Joe Rogan calls it summoning the muse,
saying that there is a creative part in
your
brain in the subconscious,
and you just need to get it out.
You need to extract it.
You need to summon it. Me,
by sitting here, sometimes deep thought,
sometimes going
through other YouTube channels,
whatever it is,
I am trying to summon those good
ideas to the top. It's crazy to me
that people put so much effort into
different
areas of their business,
but they won't devote one hour a day to
just coming up
with new content ideas and strategies.
Sometimes I take the Nutonic focus
pouches, chuck them under a gum, go for a
walk. These are back in stock in the UK,
by the way, very soon.
Get it in the gum, go for a walk.
And I don't come home till I've got some
good
content ideas. I'm going to be flying.
I've had a lot of them today.
Another benefit to having this location
is, if I ever want to network with someone
or meet someone for the first time,
I don't want to bring them to my house
or go
for a noisy cafe. Go, "Hey,
here's the address of the gym.
Come through." Whether that's meeting up
with clients, whether it's meeting up with
prospects. Whatever it is,
come to the gym. Happy days.
It is a place away from home
that I can conduct those types of
meetings.
But the point I want to make clear is,
for so many of you, having a space
that you
could utilize would bring you a
significant return on investment to the
situation you're currently in. And even
if it doesn't, it will soon over time and
compound.
It doesn't have to be something as big as
this.
But even just having a room where you can
go and summon the muse for creativity.
Somewhere you can go to be yourself
and express yourself in content.
Even if it's going somewhere where people
and your neighbors can't hear you
shouting through the walls.
But the one caveat to this, Darren,
is you can't have
it all. You can't keep costs low,
record everything from home, but get the
results that other people get from having
a space.
The majority of businesses need to employ
loads of employees.
They need to have an office.
They need to agglomerate to a central
location in a
business district. For any of you that
are taking your business online, you have
the opportunity to do this from wherever
you want in the world.
And that is something
that you shouldn't take for granted.
I'm not living where I ideally wanted to
live because to me,
having a bigger house
and having a space to be creative in
is tantamount to the
success I'm going to have over the next
five and 10 years.
Every time I've got to wait for a booking,
wait for a studio, wait for a gym to go
record content in, I am losing time.
I am losing ground,
and I am taking a loss of the creative
juices that
I have. [chuckles] They're only finite.
If I don't film something,
I'm going to lose the ambition to film it.
Unfortunately, this game online,
what we're doing here,
is what I call player V player. It
is zero sum.
There's myself and other competitors,
and if I don't win your business,
you go to
them. For me to win, they have to lose.
And in a player V player game,
the thing that you want more than anything
else is
an edge.
And I'm getting the edge paying for this.
I'm getting the edge paying for him.
I'm getting the edge paying for paid ads.
And it's ultimately who gets
that edge who wins.
This game isn't just about content.
It's not just about email marketing.
It's not just about delivering amazing
service to your clients.
It's about outmaneuvering your competitors
whenever possible.
And if you don't, they will. And
if they do it and you don't, it could take
you five years to realize that's the
mistake that you made, and that's why you
didn't win the battle.
For me to make the money I would need to
from this space,
having this as a gym,
I would need thousands of members.
I would need cleaners.
I need to give people access.
We now live in a world where it makes me
way more
money to have a gym
that no one comes to than have a gym
that has hundreds or even
thousands of members. Let that sink in.
This space gives me somewhere to take my
ideas, put them into content.
Those content that gets more views,
more click-through rates,
more watch hours,
gets me leads.
Those leads convert into clients.
Those clients give me money where I can
reinvest into the funnel from the top
again.
There are two ways for you to level up
your productivity.
Drink Nutonic,
and get yourself a space where you can be
you.
You can build a brand, fall forward,
and win your niche.
Hope you enjoyed that video.
There's going to be a link for you to work
with me
below.
If you wanted to watch the video about why
you need to get a cool car in
your 30s, check out this one here. Bosch.